Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/darius-walker-2364a433 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nonprofit Organizations Coaching Digital Media

Languages

English

Honors-Awards

Emmy Award
Peabody Award
NY-NABJ "Trailblazer Award"
Peabody
Peabody Award

Darius Walker

President Darius Walker Media New York, New York, United States

Summary

Darius Walker is the founder and President of Darius Walker Media. Darius Walker Media is a global consulting firm which advises clients in the digital space on strategy, programming and growth and engagement. Our clients have included CBS News, The Griot and many others.

Previous to creating Darius Walker Media he was the Senior Vice President and Senior Executive Producer of CBSN, CBS News' 24 hour streaming network. In this role, Walker oversaw the day to day and long term strategic vision for CBSN's USA and international programming, editorial, production and operations. CBSN is now available globally in over 100 countries.

CBSN drove strong viewership growth, setting new viewership records in November 2020 which is now the top-ranked month for total streams. CBSN recorded over 1 billion streams globally in 2020.

Prior to joining CBS News, Walker was the Vice President and NY-Northeast Bureau Chief for CNN. In this capacity he oversaw all editorial resources and assignments for CNN's team of correspondents, producers, photojournalists and editors based in CNN's largest national bureau. Before his New York assignment, Walker was the Senior Director of newsgathering for CNN's Washington, D.C., bureau.

Walker also served as vice president of CNN Business News, where he managed business news coverage across various CNN platforms; Supervising producer for CNNfn's Atlanta operations; and as senior broadcast producer for the business news program, Lou Dobbs Moneyline. From 1996 to 1998, Walker worked for CNN's national desk in Atlanta as a senior editor and producer.

Before joining CNN, he was the Managing Editor and the Executive Producer for special projects at NBC's flagship station, WNBC in

New York. From 1992 to 1994, he worked at WAGA-TV, the then CBS affiliate in Atlanta, where he was the Managing Editor and led the Emmy Award-winning coverage of the Atlanta stadium fire.

Walker has won several Emmy, Peabody and Dupont awards. He is also the recipient of the New York Association of Black Journalists "Trailblazer" Award for Excellence in Journalism and the Tuck School of Business (Dartmouth College) award for Business Reporting. Walker is also is the winner of the 2018 Digital Diversity Network's Change Agent award.

Experience

Darius Walker Media President December 2014 - Present (8 years 9 months) New York

CBSN

Senior Vice President and Sr Executive Producer September 2020 - February 2022 (1 year 6 months) New York

CBS News Digital
Vice President and Sr Executive Producer
July 2018 - September 2020 (2 years 3 months)
Greater New York City Area

CNN

7 years 5 months

Vice President & NY-Northeast Bureau Chief September 2013 - December 2014 (1 year 4 months) CNN New York

New York Bureau Chief August 2007 - December 2014 (7 years 5 months)

CNN Washington DC Sr. Director of News Coverage August 2004 - August 2007 (3 years 1 month)

CNNfn NY

Vice President of Business News January 2001 - August 2004 (3 years 8 months) NY NY

WNBC NY Managing Editor 1994 - 1996 (2 years)

Fox 5 WAGA Atlanta Managing Editor 1992 - 1994 (2 years)

ABC News NY Assignment Editor/Producer 1988 - 1992 (4 years)

WNEV TV (WHDH) Boston Assignment Editor/Producer 1986 - 1988 (2 years)

WBZ TV/Radio Boston Writer/Producer/Editor 1980 - 1986 (6 years)

Education

Northeastern University Journalism · (1978 - 1980)

UCLA Anderson School of Management NAMIC Executive Management and Leadership